<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STAT 140-04:  Introduction to the Ideas and Applications of Statistics on Stat 140 (Fall 2020)</title>
    <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/</link>
    <description>Recent content in STAT 140-04:  Introduction to the Ideas and Applications of Statistics on Stat 140 (Fall 2020)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Office hours</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/hours.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/hours.html</guid>
      <description>Office hours schedule Below is a calendar with office hours. You can directly add these events to your own Google Calendar. You can join virtual office hours by adding the event to your own calendar. These office hours are only for those officially enrolled in the course.   Teaching team Instructor  Shan Shan (she/her)  Assistant Professor Department of Math and Statistics Mount Holyoke College email: sshan at mtholyoke dot edu website: https://sshanshans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/schedule.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/schedule.html</guid>
      <description>Course Map  Daily schedule Note: This schedule may be updated as the module progresses. Due dates for the homework and project will not be changed.

 Week Date Lesson Reading Slides Tutorials DC HW Project   Week 01 Wed, Oct 21 Welcome to Statistics and Data Science          Thur, Oct 22 Data basics          Fri, Oct 23 Statistics to illuminate         Week 02 Mon, Oct 26 Categorical variable: barplot          Tue, Oct 27 Categorical variable: relationship          Wed, Oct 28 Numerical variable: histogram shape and summary          Thur, Oct 29 Numerical variable: robust statistics          Fir, Oct30 Putting it all together         Week 03 Mon, Nov 02 Numerical variable: relationship          Tue, Nov 03 Election day (no class)          Wed, Nov 04 Linear model (last day to withdraw without a W)          Thur, Nov 05 How well does a linear model fit          Fir, Nov 06 Linear regression condition         Week 04 Mon, Nov 09 Randomness and sampling overview          Tue, Nov 10 Experiments and observational studies          Wed, Nov 11 Sampling distribution          Thur, Nov 12 Normal model          Fir, Nov 13 Central limit theorem         Week 05 Mon, Nov 16 Confidence interval          Tue, Nov 17 Interpretation of confidence interval          Wed, Nov 18 One proportion          Thur, Nov 19 Comparing two proportions          Fir, Nov 20 Bootstrapping method         Week 06 Mon, Nov 23 Proposal presentation          Tue, Nov 24 Proposal presentation         Week 07 Mon, Nov 30 Hypothesis testing          Tue, Dec 01 P-value          Wed, Dec 02 Compute P-value with R          Thur, Dec 03 Decision making with hypothesis testing          Fir, Dec 04 Hypothesis testing examples         Week 08 Mon, Dec 07 Inference for regression          Tue, Dec 08 Inference for regression          Wed, Dec 09 Speaker and writer&amp;#39;s workshop          Thur, Dec 10 Group presentation          Fir, Dec 11 Group presentation         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/policies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/policies.html</guid>
      <description>Inclusion &amp;amp; Accessibility  This course is designed to be welcoming and accessible to all students. It is my goal for our learning environment to facilitate learning and intellectual development for everyone. If something was said in class (by anyone) that made you feel uncomfortable, or if there is some aspect of class that is not welcoming or accessible to you, please let me know immediately.
  Academic Accommodations   AccessAbility Services is the office on campus that determines academic accommodations for students with disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Help</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/tips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/tips.html</guid>
      <description>Logistics  How can I succeed in this class? How I should ask for TAs to help me debug the code?  R related  How to Install R on Windows, Mac OS X, and Ubuntu?  Imposter syndrome  Why some of my classmates just got the concept/did the programming assignment so fast? Am I not good enough?   Q: How can I succeed in this class? [Adapted from Albert Kim]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>