<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STAT 140:  Introduction to the Ideas and Applications of Statistics on Stat 140 (Fall 2020)</title>
    <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/</link>
    <description>Recent content in STAT 140:  Introduction to the Ideas and Applications of Statistics on Stat 140 (Fall 2020)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/schedule.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/schedule.html</guid>
      <description>  Date Topic Formative Assignments Evaluative Assignments     Unit 1 Data Summary and Visualization I     Aug 24 (M) Welcome and introduction to statistics (html)     Aug 25 (T) Data basics (html) 01 Data Camp, 01 Quiz, 01 Exercise    Aug 26 (W) Categorical variable: distributions and proportional thinking (html) 02 Quiz, 02 Exercise    Aug 27 (TH) Categorical variable: relationship between two variables (html) 03 Quiz, 03 Exercise    Aug 28 (F) Categorical variable: working in R (html) 02 Data Camp, 04 Exercise EA1 (due Sep 04)   Unit 2 Data Summary and Visualization II     Aug 31 (M) Numerical variable: histograms and shapes (html) 04 Quiz, 05 Exercise    Sep 01 (T) Numerical variable: summary of histograms (html) 05 Quiz, 06 Exercise    Sep 02 (W) Numerical variable: relationship, association and correlation (html) 06 Quiz, 07 Exercise    Sep 03 (TH) Relationship between numerical and categorical variable (html) 03 Data Camp    Sep 04 (F) Putting it all together: exploratory data analysis (html) 07 Quiz, 08 Exercise EA2 (due Sep 11)   Unit 3 Basic Regression     Sep 08 (T) Introdution to linear models (html) 08 Quiz    Sep 09 (W) How useful is your linear model (html) 09 Quiz, 09 Exercise    Sep 10 (TH) Linear regression conditions (html) 10 Quiz, 10 Exercise    Sep 11 (F) Regression over a categorical variable (html) 11 Quiz, 11 Exercise EA3 (due Sep 18)   Unit 4 Sampling     Sep 14 (M) Introduction to sampling (html) Mid-module break: nothing due    Sep 15 (T) Designed experiments and observational studies (html) 12 Quiz, 12 Exercise    Sep 16 (W) Sampling distribution (html) 13 Quiz, 13 Exercise    Sep 17 (TH) Simulation based inference I (html) 14 Quiz, 14 Exercise    Sep 18 (F) Simulation based inference II (html) 15 Exercise EA4 (due Sep 27)   Unit 5 Basic Probability     Sep 21 (M) A probability excursion (html) 15 Quiz, 16 Exercise    Sep 22 (T) Binomial distribution (html) 16 Quiz, 17 Exercise    Sep 23 (W) Binomial testing (html) 18 Exercise    Sep 24 (TH) Normal distribution (html) 19 Exercise    Sep 25 (F) Project bootcamp (html)  EA5 (due Oct 02)   Unit 6 CLT based inference     Sep 28 (M) Central Limit Theorem (CLT) (html) 20 Exercise    Sep 29 (T) CLT based confidence interval (html) 21 Exercise    Sep 30 (W) CLT based hypothesis testing (html) 22 Exercise    Oct 01 (TH) Project workshop I     Oct 02 (F) Project workshop II (html)  EA6, EA7 (due Oct 09)   Unit 7 Topics in Inference     Oct 05 (M) Mutiple means and proportions     Oct 06 (T) Project workshop III     Oct 07 (W) Statistics, AI and Ethics     Oct 08 (TH) Project workshop IV     Oct 09 (F) Project workshop V     Unit X Tell your story with data     Oct 12 (M) Concluding remarks      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/policies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sshanshans.github.io/stat140/policies.html</guid>
      <description>Inclusion &amp;amp; Accessibility This course is designed to be welcoming and accessible to all students. It is my goal for our learning environment to facilitate learning and intellectual development for everyone. If something was said in class (by anyone) that made you feel uncomfortable, or if there is some aspect of class that is not welcoming or accessible to you, please let me know immediately.
 Academic Accommodations AccessAbility Services is the office on campus that determines academic accommodations for students with disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>